kids-world-travel-guide.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy for Kids World Travel Guide: Latest Update

#### Privacy Policy

Here you will find the privacy policy of Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com.

We recognize that your privacy is important. 

This document outlines the types of personal information we receive and collect when you use Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard information. We hope this will help you make an informed decision about sharing personal information with us. 

Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com strives to maintain the highest of standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all our operations. Likewise, we are dedicated to protecting our clients’ and online visitors’ privacy on our website.

 **Personal Information**

Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com collects personally identifiable information from the visitors of our website only on a voluntary basis. 

Personal information collected on a voluntary basis (such as for our annual writing competition) may include name, postal address, email address, company name and telephone number.

This information is collected if you request information from us, sign up to join our email list or request some other service or information from us. 

The information collected is internally reviewed, used to improve the content of our website, notify our visitors of updates, and respond to visitor inquiries. Once information is reviewed, it is discarded or stored in our files.

Personal information received from any visitor will be used only for internal purposes and will not be sold or provided to third parties.

 **Use of Cookies and Web Beacons**

We may use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. 

A cookie is a string of information that Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com stores on your computer, which your browser provides to our site each time you return to the site. We use cookies to help us identify and track visitors, their use of our website, and their website access preferences.

The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have come to the site for the first time, or have returned to a specific page. If you personalize the site's pages, or register with any of our site's services, a cookie enables www.Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com to recall your specific information on subsequent visits.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying settings in your browser; however, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the site.

A web beacon is a transparent image file used to monitor your journey around a single website or collection of sites. They are commonly used in association with cookies to understand how visitors interact with the pages and content on the pages of a website.

 **Google Analytics cookies**

As you browse this website, Google Analytics and advertising cookies will be placed on your computer to collect demographic and interest information, but we do not tie the cookie to any personal information that you provide to us. 

Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com use information from Google Analytics to track the number of visits to the website, browsers and operating systems. No personally identifiable information is obtained from these cookies. We use the information that Google Analytics generates relating to our website to create reports about the use of the site. These reports allow us to update the site and improve your usage of it.

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of this website. Google Analytics collects demographic and interest data, and generates statistical and other information about website use, by means of cookies. These cookies are kept on your computer. We share this information with Google, which will store and use this information on its servers. _[Google's privacy policy can be found here](https://policies.google.com/privacy)_.

If you do not wish your data to be collected via Google Analytics, you may use their [_opt-out tool_](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) _._

 **Advertising Cookies**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our website. These companies use cookies and web beacons in their ads to ascertain how many times you’ve seen an advertisement. No personally identifiable information you give us is provided to them for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information from our website. You may opt out of personalized ads for over 125 different ad networks. _[Click here to do opt out.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)_

Some third-party advertisements are served by Google. Google's cookie enables it to serve ads to our visitors based on their visits to other sites on the Web. You may opt out of personalized ads by visiting the _[Google ad opt-out page](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated)._

The following link from Google provides more information about how Google manages data in its ad products. [_Click here for more info._](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

Other third-party advertisements may be provided by Google, which uses the Double-Click cookie to serve ads. This cookie enables Google to serve ads to users based on their visits to sites on the Web. You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the [ _Google ad and content network privacy polic_](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) _y.  _  

Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies automatically, or notify you when a cookie is being requested. Privacy software can be used to override web beacons. Taking either of these actions should not cause a problem with our site, should you so choose. 

 **Refusing Cookies**

You can set your browser to accept or refuse all cookies automatically, or notify you when a cookie is being requested. Taking this action should not cause a problem with the continued use of our site. Consult the Help section of your browser for guidance on how to refuse all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is requested.

If you choose to refuse Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com's cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the site.

 **Personally Identifiable Information**

Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com may collect and use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To run and operate our site.
  * To display content on the site correctly.
  * To improve customer service.
  * To help us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * To personalize your user experience.
  * To understand how our users as a group use the services and resources provided on our site.
  * To improve our site.
  * To improve our products and services.
  * To run a promotion, contest, survey or other site feature.
  * To send information to you that you agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to you.
  * To send periodic emails, which may include electronic newsletters and/or autoresponder series of emails.
  * To respond to your enquiries, questions, and/or other requests.

Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com may collect personally identifiable information from you in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when you visit our site, register on the site, or fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our site.  

If you complete a form, we will require your name and your email address, and will ask for information relevant to the purpose of the form.  

Specifically, if you subscribe to our newsletter, we will ask for your first name and will require your email address. 

This site also uses Facebook commenting. Facebook stores all of your comments and may show them on your timeline, depending on your Facebook settings. We further use Pinterest and Twitter commenting. These also use your comments depending on their settings.

You can always refuse to supply personally identifiable information and visit our site anonymously. However, it may prevent you from engaging in certain site-related activities.

If we make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information, we will inform you by placing a notice on our site. We will use personal information received from you for internal purposes only and will not sell it or provide it to third parties.

We also collect each visitor's IP address, which helps us combat spam and fraud. We do not use IP addresses for any other purpose.

 **Non-personal Information**

In some cases, we may collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. The information collected is used solely for internal review and not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes.

 **Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act**

This website is directed to adults and teenager over the age of 16 years; we will not knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under the age of 16 years. Anyone under the age of 16 must provide parental consent to use this site. 

We operate our site in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a person under the relevant age without parental consent, we take steps to delete that information.

 **Release of Information**

If Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com is sold, the information we have obtained from you through your voluntary participation in our site may transfer to the new owner as a part of the sale in order that the service being provided to you may continue. In that event, you will receive notice through our website of that change in control and practices, and we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the purchaser honors any opt-out requests you might make of us.

 **Data Storage**

Personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information collected by this site is stored on our host's servers. That host is SiteSell Inc., located at 1000 Saint-Jean Boulevard, Suite 702, Pointe-Claire, QC H9R 5P1 Canada.

 **How You Can Correct or Remove Information**

We provide this privacy policy as a statement to you of our commitment to protect your personal information. If you have submitted personal information through our website and would like that information is deleted from our records or would like to update or correct that information, please click on this link and use our [Contact Us page](https://www.kids-world-travel-guide.com/contact.html).

 **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this page. If there is a material change in our privacy practices, we will indicate on our site that our privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the new privacy policy; and where required by law, we will obtain your consent or give you the opportunity to opt out of such changes.

 **Updates and Effective Date**

Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com reserves the right to make changes in this policy as required by law. We will provide information on necessary updates and also encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will always know what information we collect and how we use it.

 **Agreeing to Terms**

If you do not agree to the Kids-World-Travel-Guide.com Privacy Policy as posted here on this website, please do not consent to the setting of cookies and the collection and storage of your personally identifiable information or do not use this site.

Your explicit consent indicates acceptance of this privacy policy in its entirety.

Last updated: 25 May 2018
